PAUL LANDRY

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PROFILE INFO

Paul is a full-stack developer with 7 years of experience and extensive and versatile coding skills.

His expertise lies in building MVPs, enterprise software, scalable microservices, REST APIs, apps, and Socket APIs, infrastructure modeling, AWS and deployment.

He is the go-to guy for any of your development needs.

CONTACT INFO



Email

happyplandry@gmail.com



Address

Winnipeg, 190 St Marys Rd Manitoba R3C 0C4

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer Solace Corporation

2019.05 - 2023.01

- Contributed to launching MVP of the redesigned version of the public site for a healthcare company using React and Angular
- Implemented SSR and SSG on SPA and decreased initial page loading speed using Next.js and Gatsby.js and improved SEO performance using sitemap
- Improved the performance of the marketplace by 20% by leveraging optimization techniques like React Hooks, Redux, and GraphQL and implemented payment gateway using Stripe
- Strongly experienced in daily code reviews, design reviews, and feature reviews in the product roadmap
- Implemented live streaming using WebRTC
- Developed a smart contract for the NFT marketplace functionality and healthcare sites using .NET
- Built a real-time communication app for the company using MERN stack and Socket.io

Frontend Developer 2016.10 - 2019.04 Cisco Systems Inc.

- Translated designs into pixel-perfect responsive UI using popular CSS frameworks such as MUI, Tailwind CSS, Chakra, and so on
- Collaborated with a design team and made user-friendly interface implemented user experience
- Used Nest.js, Apollo, Prisma, and PostgreSQL on several healthcare websites
- Wrote tests for UI components and APIs using Enzyme, Jest, and Cypress
- Built the admin system of the financial agency using MERN stack

PAUL LANDRY

MY LANGUAGES JavaScript TypeScript HTML / CSS PHP Python Java SQL MY SKILLS React/Redux Vue.js/Vuex Next.js/Gatsby Angular Node.js/Express Laravel Django

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend developer CoreLink World

2015.05 - 2016.10

- Developed a website to collect and save information concerning the client's Agile software development process
- Built 5 websites such as a blog site using JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, SASS
- Customized the complex and reusable components in **React**, as a result optimized the project and reduced the loading speed
- Provided APIs and libraries for other developers to use
- Created a fully encrypted chat app with several features like notifications and media shares in just over a month period; using technologies like Firebase and React Native

EDUCATION HISTORY

Bachelor Of Computer Science University of Toronto

2011 - 2015